The school is not allowing her to attend classes since we have not been able to pay Tk900, Shabnams mother <PERSON>Baby Begum</PERSON> said.
Asked why she had not enrolled <PERSON>Shabnam</PERSON> to a government school, the dejected mother said: Because they ask for Tk300-400 for birth registration.
I work to pay my school fees and to collect the money for birth registration, he said.
<PERSON>Meherunnesa</PERSON>, another resident of the slum, said her daughter <PERSON>Sabihas</PERSON> marriage almost broke off two months ago because she did not have a birth registration number.
The grooms family left the ceremony when the kazi told us that the marriage cannot be registered without the bride and grooms birth registration numbers.
Later, with the help of some NGO workers in our locality, my daughter got her birth registered on an urgent basis for Tk300 at the city corporation, she told the <ORGANIZATION>Dhaka Tribune</ORGANIZATION>.
<PERSON>Suriya Zannat</PERSON>, child protection officer at <ORGANIZATION>World Vision</ORGANIZATION>, a charity organisation for children, said a number of children in the slum are dropping out of school because they cannot get birth registration number that the government schools ask for, and they cannot afford going to private schools.
We contacted local city corporation officials about this but did not get any response, she said.
<PERSON>Sazzad Hossain</PERSON>, <ORGANIZATION>Ward</ORGANIZATION> 2 councillor in <LOCATION>Mirpur</LOCATION>, said: There are no pending applications on my desk as I complete all formalities as soon as possible when residents of my area send in their applications.
When the <ORGANIZATION>Dhaka Tribune</ORGANIZATION> contacted <PERSON>Md Nayeb Ali</PERSON>, zonal executive officer at <ORGANIZATION>Dhaka North City Corporation</ORGANIZATION> (<ORGANIZATION>DNCC</ORGANIZATION>) for <LOCATION>Mirpur</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Pallabi</LOCATION>, he said birth registration was not his responsibility.
I have asked all the applicants to submit their documents for the registration.
I will personally make sure that the registrations are done properly, she said.'

Timestamp: 2016-06-14 01:24:00

Category: bangladesh
